Finding Aid for John J. Carton Papers, 1883-1921
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John J. Carton Papers 1883-1921
Carton, John J. (John Jay), 1856-1934.
851360 Aa/2; AC
Flint, Michigan, attorney and Republican state representative. Correspondence concerning the automotive industry, particularly his firms dealing with the General Motors Corporation and other automobile companies; also papers concerning state politics, the Republican Party, and the Constitutional Convention of 1907-1908; also docket books, 1883-1921, with record of cases handled by Carton and his partners.
17 linear feet
3 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Harry G. Gault (donor no. 2753 ) and came to the library in 1950.
The collection is open to research.
John J. Carton was born in Clayton, Genesee County, Michigan in 1856. He was educated in Clayton and Flint schools. In 1877 he accepted a position with Niles & Cotcher, Flushing, Michigan, merchants, as a bookkeeper. He remained there until December 1880 when he was elected clerk of Genesee County where he served for four years. During that same period, Carton studied law and was admitted to the bar. He formed a partnership with George H. Durand under the firm name of Durand and Carton. He was a member of the Michigan House of Representatives from 1899 to 1905 and served as Speaker of the House in 1901 and 1903. At the opening of the Constitutional Convention of 1907, Carton was chosen president.
The collection has been divided into the following series: Correspondence, 1900-1920; Masonic Papers, 1909-1920; Railroad, 1919-1920; Law Materials.
Subjects:
Automobile industry and trade--Michigan.; Banks and banking--Michigan.; Carton, John J. (John Jay), 1856-1934.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Draft.; Elections--Michigan--1904.; Elections--Michigan--1906.; Elections--Michigan--1908.; Elections--Michigan--1910.; Elections--Michigan--1912.; Elections--Michigan--1914.; Elections--Michigan--1918.; Elections--Michigan--1920.; Flint (Mich.); Freemasonry--Michigan.; Lawyers--Michigan--Flint.; McMillan, James, 1838-1902.; Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1907-1908); Michigan Manufacturer's Association.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Michigan--Politics and government--1917-1921.; Railroads--Michigan.; Republican Party (Mich.); Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.; World War, 1914-1918.
Contributors:
Alger, Frederick Moulton, 1876-1933.; Alger, R. A. (Russell Alexander), 1836-1907.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927.; Bliss, Aaron Thomas, 1837-1906.; Blodgett, John Wood, 1860-1951.; Bray, Everett Lewis, 1864-; Buick Motor Company.; Burrows, Julius C. (Julius Caesar), 1837-1915.; Burton, Clarence Monroe, 1853-1932.; Carton, Augustus C.; Chevrolet Motor Car Company.; Chrysler, Walter Percy, 1875-1940.; Denby, Edwin, 1870-1929.; Detroit United Railway.; Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.; Diekema, Gerrit John, 1859-1930.; Dort Motor Car Company.; Dow, Herbert Henry, 1866-1930.; Durant, William Crapo, 1861-1947.; Durant-Dort Carriage Company.; Fellows, Grant, 1865-1929.; Flint Gas Company (Mich.); General Motors Corporation.; Genesee County War Board (Mich.); Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Hemans, Lawton T. (Lawton Thomas), 1864-1916.; Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.; Kelley, Patrick Henry, 1867-1925.; King, Paul H.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; Marshall, Thomas R. (Thomas Riley), 1854-1925.; Michigan State Bar Association.; Michigan Railroad Commission.; Michigan War Preparedness Board.; Mott, Charles Stewart, 1875-1973.; Newspaper Cartoonists' Association of Michigan.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Pere Marquette Railroad.; Poindexter, Miles, 1868-1946.; Procter, William Cooper, 1862-1934.; Rich, John Treadway, 1841-1926.; Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934.; Smith, Henry Cassorte, 1859-1911.; Smith, Samuel William, 1852-1931.; Smith, William Alden, 1859-1932.; State League of Republican Clubs of Michigan.; Stearns, Justus S. (Justus Smith), b. 1845.; Tawas Sugar Company.; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.
- Correspondence
  - Undated 1900-June 1904, 31 folders (Box 1)
  - July 1904-December 1905, 43 folders (Box 2)
  - 1906-March 1907, 38 folders (Box 3)
  - April 1907-April 1908, 37 folders (Box 4)
  - May 1908-May 1909, 38 folders (Box 5)
  - June 1909-June 1910, 37 folders (Box 6)
  - July 1910-July 1911, 36 folders (Box 7)
  - August 1911-August 1912, 36 folders (Box 8)
  - September 1912-September 1913, 37 folders (Box 9)
  - October 1913-December 1914, 40 folders (Box 10)
  - 1915-February 1916, 36 folders (Box 11)
  - March 1916-June 1917, 44 folders (Box 12)
  - July 1917-April 1918, 37 folders (Box 13)
  - May 1918-May 1919, 37 folders (Box 14)
  - June 1919-April 1920, 32 folders (Box 15)
  - May 1920-December 1920, 8 folders (Box 16)
- Masonic Papers
  - March 1909-1915, 35 folders (Box 16)
  - 1916-May 1920, 32 folders (Box 17)
- Railroad Papers
  - September 1919-September 1920, 10 folders (Box 17)
- Law Materials
  - Docket books with record of cases handled by Carton and his partners 1883-1921 (Volume 1)
  - Docket books with record of cases handled by Carton and his partners 1883-1921 (Volume 2)
    (continued)
  - Docket books with record of cases handled by Carton and his partners 1883-1921 (Volume 3)
Partial Index to Correspondence
Alger. Frederick Moulton.1876-1933.
Oct. 17, 1910, Jan. 10, 1920, Jan. 14, 1920, Jan. 20, 1920, Feb. 16, 1920, Mar. 16, 1920, Apr. 1, 1920, Apr. 7, 1920, Apr. 12, 1920
Alger, R. A. (Russell Alexander), 1836-1907.
Feb. 2, 1904, Jan. 23, 1905, Feb. 27, 1905, Apr. 6, 1905, May 27, 1905, May 29, 1905, Jan. 5, 1906
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
May 5, 1905, May 22, 1905, May 23, 1905, May 26, 1905, Apr. 9, 1901
Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927.
Feb. 11, 1907
Bliss, Aaron Thomas, 1837- 1906.
Sept. 1, 1903, Sept. 28, 1903, Dec. 23, 1903, Dec. 29, 1903, Feb. 12, 1904
Blodgett, John Wood, 1860-1951.
June 1, 1908, June 13, 1908, June 6, 1912, June 8, 1912, June 12, 1912
Bray, Everett Lewis, 1864-
[Correspondence throughout]
Burrows, Julius C. (Julius Caesar), 1837-1915.
Feb. 1, 1904, Jan. 29, 1904, Dec. 3, 1904, Jan. 23, 1904, Feb. 20, 1905, Feb. 27, 1905, Dec. 28, 1905
Jan. 11, 1906, Apr. 25, 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909, Dec. 5, 1910, Feb. 21, 1911, Mar. 6, 1911
Burton, Clarence Monroe, 1853-1932.
May 6, 1908, May 7, 1908, May 8, 1908, Dec. 28, 1908
Carton, Augustus C.
[Correspondence throughout]
Chrysler, Walter Percy, 1875-1940.
Nov. 12, 1918, May 22, 1919, May 29, 1919, Apr. 28, 1919, Oct. 28, 1919
Denby, Edwin, 1870-1929.
Dec. 7, 1904, Jan. 23, 1905, Feb. 7, 1905, Sept. 4, 1907, Jan. 20, 1908, Dec. 16, 1912, Aug. 26, 1919
Detroit United Railway.
Sept. 1, 1903, Nov. 24, 1903, 1904-1918
Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.
Sept. 25, 1907, Jan. 10, 1910, Jan. 11, 1910
Diekema, Gerrit, John, 1859-1930.
Feb. 8, 1904, Oct. 20, 1904, 1907, Mar. 30, 1912
Dort Motor Car Company.
1916-1920
Dow, Herbert Henry, 1866-1930.
Oct. 16, 1916, Oct. 18, 1918, Oct. 24, 1918
Durant, William Crapo, 1861-1947.
[Correspondence throughout]
Durant-Dort Carriage Company.
1903-1915
Fellows, Grant, 1865-1929.
Feb. 1, 1904, Jan. 24, 1905, Jan. 23, 1905, Oct. 5, 1907, Oct. 14, 1907, Oct. 15, 1907, Nov. 1, 1907, 1909, Aug. 26, 1910, Aug. 29, 1910, Sept. 22, 1910, Sept. 22, 1910, Sept. 14, 1912, Jan. 31, 1913
Flint Gas Company.
1904-1913
General Motors Corporation
1909-1912, 1916, 1919-1920
Geneseee County War Board (Mich.)
1918-1919
Groesbeck, Alexander J., 1873-1953.
May 13, 1908, May 15, 1908, July 14, 1908, Aug. 19, 1908
Hemans, Lawton T. (Lawton Thomas), 1864-1916.
Aug. 29, 1905, Sept. 1, 1905, Sept. 15, 1905, June 20, 1907, Oct. 8, 1907, Oct. 11, 1907, Nov. 7, 1908, Feb. 20, 1911, Jan. 3, 1912, Jan. 9, 1912, Feb. 8, 1912, Dec. 4, 1914
Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.
Mar. 21, 1911, Mar. 23, 1911, Mar. 25, 1911, Mar. 27, 1911
Kelley, Patrick Henry, 1867-1925.
Feb. 8, 1904, July 2, 1904, Dec. 6, 1904, Dec. 21, 1904, Jan. 23, 1905, Mar. 22, 1906, Oct. 12, 1910, 1911, 1912, 1913, Jan. 10, 1914, Feb. 18, 1914, Apr. 24, 1915, Jan. 21, 1916, May 22, 1916, May 24, 1916, May 26, 1916, 1917-1920
King, Paul H.
May 31, 1907, Aug. 6, 1907, Aug. 14, 1907, Sept. 18, 1907, Oct. 24, 1907, Oct. 25, 1907, Nov. 29, 1907, 1908, 1909, Aug. 7, 1912, 1913, Feb. 10, 1915, Feb. 20, 1915, Sept. 27, 1915, May 25, 1916, June 24, 1916, Oct. 5, 1917
Feb. 11, 1918, Mar. 5, 1918, Mar. 7, 1918, Mar. 12, 1918, Mar. 22, 1918, Oct. 16, 1918, Jan. 3, 1919, Jan. 9, 1919, Feb. 17, 1919, Feb.24, 1919
Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.
Oct. 8, 1904, 1910
Marshall, Thomas R. (Thomas Riley), 1854-1925.
Sept. 28, 1914, Oct. 3, 1914, Oct. 21, 1914, Nov. 3, 1914, Apr. 3, 1917, July 9, 1917, July 16, 1917
Michigan Manufacturers Association.
Feb. 20, 1907, Feb. 22, 1907, June 20, 1907, Dec. 9, 1909, Nov. 14, 1910, Dec. 7, 1910, Dec. 9, 1910, Dec. 17, 1910, Feb. 22, 1911, Nov. 4, 1911, Feb. 26, 1912
Michigan Railroad Commission.
1907 -1920
Michigan State Bar Association.
Sept. 28, 1903, Oct. 27, 1903, Feb. 15, 1904, Mar. 5, 1904, Jan. 1, 1905, July 24, 1905, 1908, 1909, Nov. 29, 1912, Mar. 1, 1913, 1914, Feb. 12, 1915, May 3, 1915, May 26, 1915, June 3, 1915, Nov. 22, 1915
Feb. 3, 1916, Jan. 1, 1917, Feb. 5, 1917, Feb. 21, 1917, May 12, 1917, Oct. 4, 1917, Apr. 5, 1918, Oct. 17, 1918
Michigan War Preparedness Board.
1917, Feb. 15, 1918, Mar. 1, 1918
Mott, Charles Stewart, 1875-1973.
1909-1913, Jan. 15, 1917, Aug. 1, 1917, Oct. 19, 1917, Dec. 5, 1917, Mar. 6, 1918, Dec. 27, 1919, Dec. 31, 1919
Newspaper Cartoonists' Association of Michigan.
Jan. 17, 1905, Apr. 4, 1905, Aug. 25, 1905, Sept. 11, 1905, Dec. 4, 1905
Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), 1860-
1910-1912, Sept. 21, 1914, Sept. 26, 1914, Aug. 31, 1915, Feb. 24, 1916, May 27, 1916, Dec. 30, 1916, Jan. 8, 1917, Dec. 12, 1917, Jan. 2, 1918, Jan. 10, 1918, Mar. 6, 1918, May 2, 1918, Dec. 20, 1918, Dec. 20, 1919, Jan. 6, 1920, Jan. 26, 1920 Jan. 27, 1920, Feb. 7, 1920
Pere Marquette Railroad.
1902, 1903, 1905, 1907, 1908, 1909-1918
Poindexter, Miles, 1868-1946.
Feb. 10, 1920, Feb. 13, 1920
Procter, William Cooper, 1862-1934.
Feb. 9, 1920, Feb. 11, 1920
Rich, John Treadway, 1841-1926.
Feb. 1, 1904, Jan. 23, 1905, May 6, 1905, Feb. 28, 1908, Feb. 29, 1908, Mar. 9, 1908, Dec. 31, 1908
Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934.
May 27, 1904, June 4, 1904, Nov. 3, 1904, Nov. 4, 1904, Nov. 28, 1904, Mar. 17, 1905, Mar. 22, 1905, Mar. 23, 1905, Mar. 24, 1905, Feb. 15, 1912
Jan. 27, 1916, Nov. 28, 1916, Dec. 1, 1916, Aug. 5, 1917, Nov. 24, 1917, Mar. 20, 1918, Mar 7, 1919, Apr. 17, 1919, Apr.28, 1919
Smith, Henry Cassorte, 1859-1911.
Jan. 22, 1904, Feb. 1, 1904, Feb. 4, 1904, Feb. 8, 1904, Mar. 17, 1905, Apr. 8, 1905, Apr. 25, 1905
Smith, Samue1 William, 1852-1931.
1903-1911, 1913-1915
Smith, William Alden, 1859-1932.
Feb. 1, 1904, Feb. 10, 1904, Feb. 20, 1904, Jan. 23, 1905, Jan. 25, 1905, Jan. 27, 1905, Feb. 10, 1905, Feb. 27, 1905, Mar. 14, 1905, Mar. 17, 1905, 1907, 1908, 1909, Dec. 20, 1910
Jan. 26, 1911, Feb. 21, 1911, Feb. 26, 1911, Mar. 6, 1911, May 1, 1911, May 5, 1911, Nov. 29, 1911
May 9, 1913, Apr. 6, 1914, Apr. 4, 1914, Oct. 7, 1914, Apr. 23, 1917, Apr. 25, 1917, Nov. 13, 1917, Nov. 14, 1917, Feb. 1, 1918
State League of Republican Clubs of Michigan.
Nov. 16, 1903, Jan. 29, 1907, Feb. 18, 1907, Aug. 19, 1907, Oct. 25, 1907, Jan. 7, 1908, Oct.23, 1912
Stearns, Justus S. (Justus Smith), 1845-
Feb. 11, 1904
Tawas Sugar Company.
1903-1906
Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.
Jan. 23, 1905, Aug. 21, 1905, Aug. 23, 1905, 1907, Dec. 26, 1908, Sept. 8, 1910, June 12, 1911
Oct. 9, 1914, Oct. 12, 1914, Jan. 18, 1915, Jan. 20, 1915, Apr. 23, 1917, May 5, 1919, Apr. 22, 1919, Apr. 24, 1919, Aug. 15, 1919
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Oct. 16, 1906, June 27, 1910, June 28, 1910, June 29, 1910, July 5, 1910, June 26, 1914, Nov. 6, 1914, Nov. 16, 1914
Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.
June 25, 1904, Nov. 5, 1904, Nov. 22, 1904, Nov. 30, 1904, Dec. 2, 1904, Jan. 23, 1905, Aug. 11, 1905, Aug. 29, 1905, Dec. 22, 1905, Jan. 5, 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909